I didn't uh didn't get into a lot of
fights growing up there were some
bullies bullies they were like I'll
knock the books out of your hands now
neither of us can read that sort of
thing
not everybody reads not everybody has to
read now because every book gets made
into a movie but book people are getting
smart they're called authors book people
they start re-releasing the book when
the movie comes out they put a picture
of the actor on the cover trick people
who like movies into buying the book
like the movie Fight Club came out they
re-released the book and people like oh
Brad Pitt's in this book
so far just words
oh
I'll fight you book and that guy fights
that book turns out the end that guy is
that book anyway it started spoil the
books
have you all seen the movie final
destination if you haven't great choice
but
foreign
here's enough information to make this
fun for all the movie final destination
is about a boy who gets on a plane the
plane takes off and explodes and
everybody dies but then he wakes up
before that happened it was a vision out
of the future he's now on the plane
before it's taken off so he's like we
gotta get out of here this is gonna blow
so they kick him off the plane because
that's what happened if you do that in
real life so far very realistic movie so
he's off the plane it does take off it
does explode just like he saw in his
vision so he's cheated death and then
death follows him and haunts him for the
rest of the movie which is what would
happen if you cheat death in a crappy
movie so I get to the end of this hour
and a half of my life and I'm like what
a crab fest and then I wake up in the
theater before it started
I'm like we gotta get out of here this
is gonna bloom
was that even a movie
[Applause]
all of you except for maybe one
some people ask how do you do it how do
you do comedy how do you get up there
every night and risk that rejection how
do you do it and here's my secret that
I'll reveal to only you and everyone
watching
I think about what's the worst thing
that could happen any given night doing
comedy is a room full of people hates me
and then I never see them again
compare that
to high school
which for me was a building full of
rooms of people same people every day so
for tonight to be worse than that y'all
would have to hate me
find me later and be like see you
tomorrow
and not just for a half hour for eight
hours a day five days a week 30 weeks a
year four years in a row can anyone do
the math on that I can that's why people
did not like me
thank you
I uh I have a special online an hour
special that you can give five stars to
if you like it you can even get five
stars to it if you don't like it just
think about how many stars there are in
the galaxy it's like 100 billion so five
is real low you got me
really stuck it to me
I did get a one star review that I liked
my favorite one star review here's how
it went guy goes I don't know about
these jokes
they might be good
he talked too fast
I'm dumb
what a Twist I love that it turned out
to be more review of himself than me
he's like I don't know about this but I
do know about this and no thank you
[Music]
I love thinking about this stuff I uh in
college I was a philosophy major or was
I
what is philosophy it's a thing or is it
you guys get it or do you okay how long
could this go on for forever it couldn't
or could it all right that's the longest
I've ever done it or is it okay as long
as there's a couple people enjoying it
or are they and
sometimes I feel like my comedies like
Tetris where people are like what is a
long one gonna come along and sort of
clear all this up you know what I mean
I took a class in college called the
philosophy of math we discussed the
great mysteries of mathematics like are
there different sizes of infinity were
numbers discovered or invented why can
we not meet women you know the great
Mysteries
oh man
I am pretty great with women let's say
why not you're not going to do any
research but the point is laughs
I am in an open marriage it's very open
it's a divorce and
we did the Jewish divorce custom where
you take a broken glass and you put it
back together
um maybe you're familiar with our
customs
50 of marriage is under divorce do you
know 50 that's so hot 50 of marriage
that's one out of every two people so
it's either gonna be you or your spouse
you know what I mean
can't argue with the numbers
yeah
I do have a girlfriend now I don't have
her she's uh not in a cage of a free
range girlfriend and uh career-range
lovely sourced organic vegan gluten-free
girlfriend that's a gfgf gluten
girlfriend and uh
we love each other we live together
we've been together for years now so
great we live together we we don't
subscribe to the traditional gender
roles you know we're like the man fixes
things and the woman cleans things so we
live in a broken dirty house
she actually does everything but uh I
love her so much I've been with her for
years longer more than double the length
of my marriage it's just the best
relationship I've ever been in like I
was only married for like two years in
my 20s and you know when you get married
every anniversary there's a traditional
material for the gift like so for our
first anniversary it's paper for a
second it's two sheets of paper that we
sign and send to lawyers and then
to even like fourth is fruit our
relationship spoiled before fruit
ripened you know
you get good ones eventually Emerald
sapphires you know silver and gold 75
years together the 70th anniversary is
diamond and I look this up this is true
do you know what 80 and 90 are Oak and
granite
that's what you make coffins and
headstones out of
Taken till death a little seriously
what's 100 formaldehyde all right
I got you something
now I don't need to bum anyone out
I mean to offer hope a silver lining of
death here's the great news about death
have you heard everything that you don't
like about life will be gone when you're
dead
every single thing that you're not
enjoying about living won't exist when
you don't
that doesn't make you feel good
and that means that you're happy right
now and that's my gift to you do you
understand
it's win-win either life is bad and it's
gonna go or life is good and it's here
right now embrace it hold on to it also
if life is good it goes and if it's bad
it's here but don't think about those
just remember the first two win-win
maybe you don't want to think about your
own death that much so let's move on you
know who else is going to die is
everyone that you don't like
every single person that's ever wronged
you will die
did die or is dying right now those are
the only options they either will did or
are dying so
if you ever get cut off in traffic and
you're like I'm gonna murder that guy
what I recommend is don't
just wait
[Applause]
and your fingerprints will be nowhere
near it
let time be your accomplice on this one
A Perfect Crime because you're not
committing it
it's like Buddhist clue if you will
there was no one in the nowhere with the
nothing
and you might be thinking but I want to
know when and how my enemy's gonna die
not just that they're gonna die and for
you spiteful people I'm working on an
app and the app is like a Google alert
but it's for obituaries so
for example
say you get cut off in traffic you just
take down the license plate number you
plug it into the app then you just go
about your business
live your life
go to your job quit your job you don't
like that job get a different job quit
that job turns out you don't like Jobs
live in the woods
live off the grid make your own grid you
have a new grid now you're in charge of
your life you're Your Own Boss that's
your job you're an artist now make your
art find that art make a family find
your family be polyamorous be asexual be
a romantic be a gender be gay or
straight or trans or sister buy or pan
or queer be binary or non-binary or
Beyond be big be bad and Beyond whatever
you want to be whatever your gender race
religion age size ability whoever you
are find yourself and love yourself find
your people love your people love your
family love your friends love your
community love your neighbors love your
country love your world love time and
space itself love the Galaxy love the
universe become the universe realize
you're the universe loving itself and
just live and love and live and love for
decades and decades and decades and
eventually you'll be 90 years old and
your phone will be like oh that jerk's
dead that's nice
[Applause]
and then you'll be like now I can die
happy and then you die in somebody
else's phone's like
and this jerk said and the circle
continues like clockwork and that app
I'm thinking of calling tick tock
hope nobody's using it please like
Kaplan thank you so much everyone
[Applause]